var questions = [
  {
    num: 1,
    question: "1: What does HTML stand for?",
    answer: "Hyper Text Markup Language",
    Option: [
      "Hyper Text Multiple Language",
      "Hyper Text Progress",
      "Hyper Tool Multi Language",
      "Hyper Text Markup Language",
    ],
  },
  {
    num: 2,
    question: "2: What is the standard markup language for creating web pages?",
    answer: "HTML",
    Option: ["XML", "HTML", "CSS", "JavaScript"],
  },
  {
    num: 3,
    question: "3: What does the 'DOCTYPE' declaration do in HTML?",
    answer: "Defines the document type and version of HTML",
    Option: [
      "Defines the document type and version of HTML",
      "Creates a new HTML document",
      "Specifies the character encoding for the document",
      "Links to an external stylesheet",
    ],
  },
  {
    num: 4,
    question: "4: Which HTML tag is used to create an unordered list by?",
    answer: "ul",
    Option: ["list", "ol", "ul", "dl"],
  },
  {
    num: 5,
    question: "5: What does the 'href' attribute specify in an anchor tag?",
    answer: "The URL of the linked resource",
    Option: [
      "The title of the linked resource",
      "The style of the linked resource",
      "The type of the linked resource",
      "The URL of the linked resource",
    ],
  },
  {
    num: 6,
    question: "6: What is the purpose of the <div> element in HTML?",
    answer: "To group and style block-level elements",
    Option: [
      "To define a hyperlink",
      "To create a line break",
      "To group and style block-level elements",
      "To insert an image",
    ],
  },
  {
    num: 7,
    question: "7: Which HTML tag is used to define a table?",
    answer: "table",
    Option: ["table", "tr", "td", "th"],
  },
  {
    num: 8,
    question: "8: What does the 'alt' attribute in an <img> tag provide?",
    answer: "Alternative text for the image",
    Option: [
      "Alignment of the image",
      "Alternate source for the image",
      "Alternative text for the image",
      "Animation effect for the image",
    ],
  },
  {
    num: 9,
    question: "9: Which tag is used to create a hyperlink in HTML?",
    answer: "a",
    Option: ["link", "a", "href", "url"],
  },
  {
    num: 10,
    question: "10: What does the 'form' element in HTML represent?",
    answer: "An HTML form for user input",
    Option: [
      "A formatted text",
      "A multimedia element",
      "A mathematical equation",
      "An HTML form for user input",
    ],
  },
];
